[
    {
        "id": "01",
        "question" : "React is also known as _____.",
        "options": [
            "ReactJS",
            "JS",
            "Both A. and B",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Both A. and B"
    },
    {
        "id": "02",
        "question" : "React is a ____.",
        "options": [
            "Web development Framework",
            "JavaScript Library",
            "jQuery",
            "Web Server"
        ],
        "answer": "JavaScript Library"
    },
    {
        "id": "03",
        "question" : " Which ReactJS function renders HTML to the web page?",
        "options": [
            "render()",
            "ReactDOM.render()",
            "renders()",
            "renders()"
        ],
        "answer": "ReactDOM.render()"
    },
    {
        "id": "04",
        "question" : "JSX stands for _____.",
        "options": [
            "JSON",
            "JSON XML",
            "JavaScript XML",
            "JavaScript and AngularJS"
        ],
        "answer": "JavaScript XML"
    },
    {
        "id": "05",
        "question" : "What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
        "options": [
            "Original DOM",
            "Virtual DOM",
            "Both A and B.",
            "None of the above."
        ],
        "answer": "Virtual DOM"
    },
    {
        "id": "06",
        "question" : "What is the default port where webpack-server runs?",
        "options": [
            "3000",
            "8080",
            "3030",
            "6060"
        ],
        "answer": "3000"
    },
    {
        "id": "07",
        "question" : "How many numbers of elements a valid react component can return?",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "Unlimited"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "id": "08",
        "question" : "What is the declarative way to render a dynamic list of components based on values in an array?",
        "options": [
            "Using the reduce array method",
            "Using the <Each /> component",
            "Using the Array.map() method",
            "With a for/while loop"
        ],
        "answer": "Using the Array.map() method"
    },
    {
        "id": "09",
        "question" : "What is a state in React?",
        "options": [
            "A permanent storage.",
            "Internal storage of the component.",
            "External storage of the component.",
            "None of the above."
        ],
        "answer": "Internal storage of the component."
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question" : "What are the two ways to handle data in React?",
        "options": [
            "State & Props",
            "Services & Components",
            "State & Services",
            "State & Component"
        ],
        "answer": "State & Props"
    },
    {
        "id": "11",
        "question" : "In ES6 - Why arrow functions are used?",
        "options": [
            "To access pointer variable",
            "To access variable of a class",
            "Both A. and B",
            "Write shorter function syntax"
        ],
        "answer": "Write shorter function syntax"
    },
    {
        "id": "12",
        "question" : "Consider the below function â€“ which is the correct syntax of arrow function?",
        "options": [
            "Msg = () => {return 'Good Morning'}",
            "Msg = () => 'Good Morning'",
            "Both A. and B",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Both A. and B"
    },
    {
        "id": "13",
        "question" : "Which is the correct arrow function to add two numbers?",
        "options": [
            "add = (a,b) => a+b;",
            "add = (a,b) => a+b;",
            "add = (a,b) => { return a+b;}",
            "Both A. and C"
        ],
        "answer": "Both A. and C"
    },
    {
        "id": "14",
        "question" : "With an arrow function - this keyword represents _____.",
        "options": [
            "Content",
            "Header object",
            "Current object",
            "Child object"
        ],
        "answer": "Header object"
    },
    {
        "id": "15",
        "question" : "Complete the below given arrow function.",
        "options": [
            "()",
            "=>",
            "()>",
            "() =>"
        ],
        "answer": "() =>"
    },
    {
        "id": "16",
        "question" : " In ES6 - Which are the keywords to define variables?",
        "options": [
            "var",
            "let",
            "const",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": "17",
        "question" : "Which is used to pass data to components from outside?",
        "options": [
            "Render with arguments",
            "props",
            "setState",
            "PropTypes"
        ],
        "answer": "props"
    },
    {
        "id": "18",
        "question" : "In ES6 - let is the block scoped version of ____.",
        "options": [
            "const",
            "function",
            "var",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "var"
    },
    {
        "id": "19",
        "question" : "Which method is used to generate lists?",
        "options": [
            "map()",
            "generate()",
            "new()",
            "maps()"
        ],
        "answer": "map()"
    },
    {
        "id": "20",
        "question" : "What is the default port where webpack-server runs?",
        "options": [
            "8000",
            "8080",
            "3000",
            "3030"
        ],
        "answer": "8080"
    }
]